Hasan Nakib

1 Newport Place, Bradford, BD8 8DU

+44 07548 657100 | hsnnkb.dev@gmail.com | Certifications | Portfolio Website

PROFILE SUMMARY

Solution-oriented software developer with industry experience capable of designing, building, testing, and deploying software under tight deadlines, pursuing a new software development role. Proficiency in many programming languages and frameworks with an eagerness to learn any new concepts. My passion for software development is also evidenced by my development of a personal portfolio website, participation in technology bootcamps, and attainment of software-related certifications.

KEY SKILLS

- Web technologies (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React).
- Agile methodologies, Scrum & Kanban.
 Certified Scrum Master.
- GIT version control systems and workflows.
- CI / CD delivery systems (Pipelines & Actions).
- Linux / Unix environments.
- Jest, Linters, webpack, Node.js.

- Native and Hybrid Mobile applications (Java, Angular, Ionic, Cordova).
- Cloud platforms, Azure, AWS, & OpenStack.
- Confident communicator and collaborator.
- Analytical and organised.
- Conscientious and empathetic.
- Initiative-taking and inquisitive.

WORK HISTORY

Software Developer Intern | Quantum Outsource

Feb 2021 - Dec 2021

- Successfully developed prototypes for an android scanner application, both as a native Java-written
 application and as a hybrid application using the Ionic framework in conjunction with Angular.
- Attained Professional Scrum Master I certification as part of training. Worked in accordance with Agile methodologies, working to 2-week time-boxed sprints and attending daily stand-up meetings.
- Implemented automated CI/CD processes with the use of pipelines to create secure code delivery systems for multiple codebases.
- Utilised Linux environments and applied modern version control system techniques (e.g., Git workflows) to assist with CI/CD processes.
- Assisted in the maintenance and patching of the operational software systems, helping deploy fixes under strict deadlines.
- Consistently recorded detailed documents of work for future reference. Created high-fidelity wireframes, converting client specification to mock-ups made in Figma.
- Efficiently researched and applied concepts and techniques to improve areas such as the development lifecycle, code delivery, platform improvement, and software system security.

Freelance Software Developer | Self Employed

Oct 2020 - Jan 2021

- Consulted with clients, communicated to understand their specifications/requirements for creating projects, e.g., websites, application prototypes.
- Designed, built, and tested software. Varies from supplying clients with wireframes of their websites to debugging faulty scripts.
- Continually deployed software, using the AWS S3 bucket system, a Lambda function, and a Rest API to host my own portfolio website that includes a functional contact form.
- Actively applied software development best practices through TDD, SOLID principles, WCAG and following Scrum and Kanban software development approaches.

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS

BSc Hons. Computing and IT (Software) | Open University Predicted First-class degree.

Oct 2019 - Oct 2023

- "Web, Mobile, and Cloud technology" module. Developed static websites (HTML, CSS, JavaScript), contact form applications (PHP & SQL), and multiple hybrid mobile applications with the use of Cordova, REST APIs, and plugins.
- Studied "Software Engineering" module, includes the software development lifecycle through the lens
 of the Unified Process, ITIL, and Agile methodologies (e.g., Scrum, Kanban, XP). Maturing
 collaboration, communication, and organisation skills.
- Expanded on cloud and technology literacy through utilising open-source cloud platform OpenStack.
 Hosted a functional web application with multiple VM instances, load-balancing and efficient data storage.
- Developed problem-solving and analytical skills through the study of "Algorithms, data structures and computability" module.

A Level | Bradford College

Sept 2017 - June 2019

3 A-levels : Mathematics, Biology, Chemistry.

GCSE | Beckfoot Upper Heaton

Sept 2012 - June 2016

9 GCSEs: A* - C

CERTIFICATIONS

- Professional Scrum Master I (PSM I)
- Microsoft Fundamentals series:
 - Azure (AZ-900)
 - Azure AI (AI-900)
 - Azure Data (DP-900)
- Security, Compliance, and Identity (SC-900)
- Power Platforms (PL-900)
- 365 (MS-900)
- Microsoft Office Specialist: Associate
- Microsoft Certified Educator

INTERESTS

Some recent extra-curricular career-developing activities include completing an online course on starting a business and attending an Atos 5-day virtual bootcamp. Additionally, I am applying to the Microsoft EMBRACE program as a potential mentee and seeking to become a member with BCS in the near future. As a personal goal, I am also completing 'The Odin Project', learning more about Full-Stack JavaScript development and extending my knowledge on web technologies.

REFERENCES

References are available upon request.